Bart McLeroy

Mediator / Arbitrator

bart@mcleroyadr.com 214-763-2577

Profile

Mediator / arbitrator with extensive experience resolving commercial disputes.

Alternative Dispute Resolution Experience

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

2015 – Present

Arbitrator for securities industry consumer / broker and broker / employer disputes.

Texas Department of Insurance

2014 - Present

Mediator for health insurance carrier / provider billing disputes.

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

2008 – Present

Arbitrator for property valuation disputes between property owners and county appraisal districts.

Dallas County Courts

2008 - 2010

Settlement week volunteer mediator for civil district courts.

SquareTrade, Inc.

2003 - 2006

Mediator for eBay buyer / seller disputes. Over 1,000 mediations conducted.

McLeroy Dispute Resolution

2002 - Present

Provide ADR services for individual and non-institutional clients.

Real Estate Experience

Jones Lang LaSalle

2003 - 2017

Provided outsourced real estate services for multinational clients. Job duties included consulting, sales, leasing, and portfolio / asset management. Worked with office, retail, industrial, land, and telecommunication sites.

Cousins Properties

1999 - 2003

Managed lease administration, forecasting, utility rebilling, \$25M in annual collections, and preparation of annual budget for 1.4 million square foot landmark commercial property.

Teaching Experience

Collin College

2018 - Present

Professor of Real Estate

Tarrant County College

2005 - 2016

Adjunct Professor of Real Estate

Education

University of Applied Sciences (Ludwigshafen, Germany)

MBA, Logistics, 2018

University of Texas at Arlington

M.S., Real Estate, 2004

University of Illinois

B.A., Economics, 1998

Professional Credentials: Texas Real Estate Broker License, Washington Real Estate Managing Broker License

ADR Training: See attached

ADR Training (Current as of November 22, 2019)

North Lake College (Irving, Texas)

Negotiation Skills for Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Mediation: A Comprehensive Introduction – 40 hours Introduction to Dispute Resolution – 40 hours Introduction to Law – 40 hours

Texas Institute for Public Problem Solving

Conflict Prevention and Management – 4 hours

National Academy of Arbitrators

Arbitration Workshop – 8 hours Arbitrator Training Workshop – 8 hours

Association for Conflict Resolution – Dallas Chapter

Mediating & Negotiating Collection Cases – 1 hour

University of Texas at Austin School of Law

International Arbitration – 8.25 hours

University of Wisconsin – Madison

Mediation Techniques for Managing Conflict – 12 hours

State Bar of Texas

Law of Arbitration – 2 hours

North Seattle College

Alternative Dispute Resolution – 50 hours

University of Texas at Arlington

Advanced ADR for Property Tax Appraisal – 8 hours

Texas Mediator Credentialing Association

2017 Mediation Symposium – 6.25 hours

Texas Comptroller of Public Accounts

Arbitration Training – 6 hours

Financial Industry Regulatory Authority

Dispute Resolution: Basic Arbitrator Training – 12 hours

Dispute Resolution: Expungement – 1.5 hours

Universiteit Leiden

International Law in Action: The Arbitration of International Disputes – 10 hours

Royal Institution of Chartered Surveyors
Acting as Advocate in Mediation – 1 hour
Arbitration - an Introduction – 1 hour

American Bar Association
Arbitration CLE – 7.5 hours
2019 Advanced Mediation Institute – 15 hours